[
{
      "question":"Which of the following Pala ruler founded the Somapuri University?",
      "optionA":"Gopala",
      "optionB":"Kumarpala",
      "optionC":"Dharmapala",
      "optionD":"Ramapala",
      "correctAns":"Dharmapala"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who was the author of Aihole Inscription ?",
      "optionA":"Ravikirti",
      "optionB":"Hiuen Tsang",
      "optionC":"Bharavi",
      "optionD":"Dandin",
      "correctAns":"Ravikirti"
   },
   {
      "question":"By whom Pallava King Mahendravarman-I got defeated?",
      "optionA":"Pulakesin II",
      "optionB":"Vikramaditya II",
      "optionC":"Yajnavarman",
      "optionD":"Pulakesin I",
      "correctAns":"Pulakesin II"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which rock edict describes Asoka’s first Dhamma Yatra to Bodhgaya and Bodhi Tree?",
      "optionA":"Major Rock Edict V",
      "optionB":"Major Rock Edict VI",
      "optionC":"Major Rock Edict VII",
      "optionD":"Major Rock Edict VIII",
      "correctAns":"Major Rock Edict VIII"
   },
   {
      "question":"The Ashoka’s Bairut inscription was brought to Allahabad by__?",
      "optionA":"Cunningham",
      "optionB":"James Princep",
      "optionC":"Feroj Shah Tughlaq",
      "optionD":"Jahangir",
      "correctAns":"Cunningham"
   },
   {
      "question":"In the Mauryan period, the duties of Mudradhyaksha were concerned with –",
      "optionA":"Forest produce",
      "optionB":"Ports",
      "optionC":"Commerce",
      "optionD":"Passports",
      "correctAns":"Passports"
   },
   {
      "question":"Mauryan Emperor Ashoka is referred as Ashokavardhana in which of the following?",
      "optionA":"Junagarh Inscription",
      "optionB":"Puranas",
      "optionC":"Nitlur minor rock edict",
      "optionD":"Maski edict",
      "correctAns":"Puranas"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following subjects are dealt in by Kalpa Sutras?",
      "optionA":"Sacrifices",
      "optionB":"Family ceremonies",
      "optionC":"Varnas, Ashramas",
      "optionD":"All of the above",
      "correctAns":"All of the above"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which among the following was the capital of Pandyas Kingdom?",
      "optionA":"Tondi",
      "optionB":"Musiri",
      "optionC":"Madurai",
      "optionD":"Kaveripattnam",
      "correctAns":"Madurai"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which among the following was the royal emblem of Pandya Kingdom?",
      "optionA":"Fish",
      "optionB":"Carp",
      "optionC":"Bow",
      "optionD":"Both a & b",
      "correctAns":"Both a & b"
   }
]